RG 137 United States Navy League, Comforts Committee, Admiral Bunce Section
Connecticut State Library
United States Navy League, Comforts Committee, Admiral Bunce Section records
1917-1918
Connecticut State Library
United States Navy League. Comforts Committee. Admiral Bunce Section
1.5 cubic feet
On July 4, 1915, a group of women in Washington, D.C. formed the Women’s Section of the Navy League. The League hoped to band women of various philosophical backgrounds under the banner of “Patriotism, Americanism, and National Defense.” The function of a Comforts Committee was to knit woolen garments for men serving in the United States Navy.
RG137
1975-002
Historical Note
On July 4, 1915, a group of women in Washington, D.C. formed the Women’s Section of the Navy League. The League hoped to band women of various philosophical backgrounds under the banner of “Patriotism, Americanism, and National Defense.” Twenty-five members of the Women’s Section in any town could organize a chapter, with chapters being named for a town, patriotic event or historic place, or historical character no longer living. The materials in this record group were created by the Comforts Committee of the Admiral Bunce Section of the Navy League. The function of a Comforts Committee was to knit woolen garments for men serving in the United States Navy.
Scope and Content
The records include correspondence, newspaper clippings, and ledgers.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
United States Navy League. Comforts Committee. Admiral Bunce Section
Places:
Hartford (Conn.) -- History -- Sources
Subjects:
United States Navy League. Comforts Committee. Admiral Bunce Section -- Records and correspondence; World War, 1914-1918 -- Connecticut -- Hartford; Patriotic societies; Women -- Societies and clubs
Document Types:
Correspondence; Clippings; Ledgers
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
The records were transferred from RG 030 on December 4, 1975.
Container List
- Records, 1917-1918
  - 1. Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
    Arranged alphabetically, by correspondent.
  - 2. General file, 1917-1918 (Box 2)
    Consists primarily of correspondence.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - 3. Miscellaneous papers, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
    - Bills, G. Fox & Co., 1917 (Box 3)
    - Clippings from newspapers (Box 3)
    - Contributors to Admiral Bunce Section, Navy League (Box 3)
    - Ledgers, 2 volumes, shared folder (Box 3)
    - Manual of voluntary aid, shared folder (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Red Cross (Box 3)
    - Stationary used by the Navy League (Box 3)
      Letterheads of: Admiral Bunce Section; Admiral Bunce Section, Comforts Committee; Bureau of Personal Accident & Health Underwriters; Walter C. Faxon.